[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：在Netscape 2中，我们添加了一个仍然存在的事件模型
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: In Netscape 2 we added an event model which is still in all
浏览器。
the browsers.
浏览器具有事件驱动的单线程编程模型。
The browser has an event driven single threaded programming model.
这是浏览器最好的地方之一。
Which is one of the best things about the browser.
每个事件都将针对特定节点。
Every event will be targeted at a particular node.
并且事件导致事件处理程序函数的调用。
And the events cause the invocation of event handler functions.
不幸的是，事件的组成真的很草率，从我的角度来看，
Unfortunately, the composition of events is really sloppy, from my perspective,
这是层混淆，有一些事件是为了
there's layer confusion, there are some events which are intended for
Widget、低级组件以及一些用于应用程序的组件，
widgets, low level components, and some intended for applications,
更高级别的组件和DOM的设计将它们混合在一起。
higher level components and the design of the dom mixes them all up.
所以你已经有了像点击和双击这样的应用程序级别的东西
So you've got application level things like click and double click
完全混合了小部件级别的东西，比如鼠标按下，鼠标移动。
completely mixed up with widget level things like mouse down, mouse move.
现在看来他们是，这里的一线希望是因为
Now it turns out they're, the silver lining here is because
每件事都暴露给每个人，这是可能的
everything was exposed to everybody, it was possible for
图书馆来清理东西，并对其施加秩序。
the libraries to come in and clean things up and impose order on it.
这很管用，因为所有的东西都是可用的，但是
And that worked because everything was available, but
如果不是必要的话情况会好得多，
it would have been much better had they not even been necessary,
如果DOM一开始就被正确设计的话。
if the dom had just been Designed correctly in the first place.
在输入事件中存在类似的层混淆。
There are similar layer confusion in the input events.
您有应用程序级别的东西，如模糊、更改和焦点
You've got application level things like blur, change, and focus and
按键和小部件级别的事情，比如向上键和向下键。
key press and widget level things like key up and key down.
再一次，一切都搞混了。
And again, it's all mixed up.
因为这一切都混在一起了。
And because it's all mixed up.
我看到应用程序把它搞混了，你会看到人们
I see applications mix it up, you'll see people
随时随地做所有这些事情，因为它是可用的。
doing all of those things all all the time everywhere because it's available.
因此，有三种方法可以将事件处理程序添加到节点。
So there are three ways of adding an event handler to a node.
有一个原始的微软模型，你可以说，node.onClick。
There is a original Microsoft model where you could say, node.onClick.
给它分配一个功能，完成。
Assign a function to it, done.
这在任何地方都有效，这很好。
And that still works everywhere, that's pretty nice.
微软决定它应该是一种方法。
Microsoft decided that it should be a method.
所以你说node.attachMethod，onclick，function。
So you say node.attachMethod, onClick, function.
好吧，WC说那还不够打字。
Okay, WC said that's not enough typing.
所以让我们让它添加事件侦听器类型f false。
So let's make it add event listener type f false.
这个假的东西有点奇怪。
And this false thing is kind of weird.
通常，如果将参数设置为关闭
Normally, if you leave a parameter off
浏览器会将其替换为undefined，这是false，但是
the browser will replace it with undefined which is false, but
在这种情况下，它真的必须是假的，否则它会失败。
in this case it really has to be false or it's gonna fail.
稍后我将解释如何使用false作为事件处理程序
In a minute I'll explain how the false is used so an event handler
接受一个可选的事件参数，它是事件如何知道发生了什么。
takes an optional event parameter which is how the event knows what happened.
不幸的是，微软没有这样做。
Microsoft unfortunately didn't do that.
相反，他们有一个全局事件变量，这是一件坏事。
Instead they had a global event variable which was a bad thing.
因此，由于这是编写事件处理程序的标准模板
So because of that this is the standard template for writing event handlers
在使用传入的事件或使用全局变量的情况下，
where either use the event that was passed in or you use the global variable,
目标要么是events目标变量，要么是
and the target is either gonna be the events target variable or
一个属性或事件源，为什么是我拥有的名称
a property or the events source, why are to names I had that
这没有任何意义，然后在那之后，你可以做你正常的事情。
it doesn't make any sense and then after that you can do your normal thing.
我不建议任何人使用我刚才展示给你的任何东西。
I don't recommend that anybody use any of what I've just shown you.
[笑]你不想用这些，因为它很痛苦
[LAUGH] You don't want to use any of that because it's painful and
只是不太好用。
it's it just doesn't work very well.
您希望改为使用库。
You want to be using libraries instead.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：因此，有两种模型用于如何进行事件传播
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So there were two models for how to do event propagation
这是在Netscape做的涓涓模型
there's the trickling model that was done at Netscape and
这是微软做的泡沫模型。
there is the bubbling model that was done at Microsoft.
所以如果滴水，你会从树的顶端开始
So if trickling you would start with the top of the tree and
您将下行到树，直到到达目标节点
you would descend down to the tree until you get to the target node and
下行过程中的任何节点都可以捕获事件并
any node along the way down can capture the event and
说我在处理，不要传下去。
say I'm taking care of it, don't pass it down.
微软，另一方面，从底部开始，他们上升到母公司，
Microsoft, on the other hand, started with the bottom and they go up parent,
家长，直到他们到达顶端。
parent, parent, parent until they get to the top.
沿途的任何节点都可以说我对此感兴趣
And any node along the way can say I'm interested in this
事件，我想处理。
event, I want to handle.
事实证明，微软的做法是正确的。
It turns out Microsoft got it right.
冒泡是正确的做法。
That bubbling up is the correct way to do that.
所以当W3C去标准化时，说好吧，我们需要想出一个标准
So when W3C went to standardize say well we need to come up with a standard for
我们如何进行事件传播。
how we do the event propagation.
我们是往下滴还是往上冒泡？
Do we do the trickling down or the bubbling up?
他们本可以说让我们做正确的那件事。
They could have said let's do the one that's right.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：嗯，他们为什么要这么做，对吗？
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Well, why would they do that, right?
所以他们取而代之的是，我们两种方式都要做。
So what they instead was, we'll do it both ways.
我们将要求浏览器向下涓涓而上。
We'll require that the browsers trickle down and bubble up.
所以他们两样都做。
So they do both.
他们首先会做一个涓涓往下的阶段，然后他们会做一个气泡向上的阶段，然后
They'll first do a trickle down phase, and they'll do a bubble up phase, and
addeventlistener上的这个false告诉你在哪个阶段做这件事。
that false that was on addeventlistener tells you on which phase you're doing it.
假的就会泡在脸上。
False will be on the bubble up the face.
那么你为什么还要关心他们为什么会有这些冒泡的东西呢？
So why do you even care why do they have this bubbling stuff at all?
它是为了解决一个可能不再是问题的问题。
It was to solve a problem that's probably not a problem anymore.
假设你正在制作一个目录页，你有100件东西
So suppose you're making a catalog page and you've got 100 things and
您可以从水库中拖动这些东西中的任何一个并将其放到页面上
you can drag any of those things from a reservoir and put them onto a page
所以，这就是你如何得到你正在编写的那些很好的创作包。
and so, that's how you've got those nice authoring package that you're writing.
所以，你有100个可拖动的元素。
And so, you've got 100 draggable elements.
这意味着您需要向每个事件处理程序添加一组事件处理程序。
That means you need to add a set of event handlers to each one of those.
你必须添加鼠标按下，鼠标向上，鼠标移动等等。
You have to add mouse down, mouse up, mouse move and so on.
这就是数以百计的事件处理程序集。
So that's hundreds of sets of event handlers.
在1995年，这花费了很长时间，当时浏览器的速度要慢得多。
In 1995, that took a long time browsers were a lot slower then.
当时JavaScript要慢得多。
JavaScript was a lot slower then.
做所有这些工作都需要时间。
It would take time to do all of that work.
因此，相反，您要做的是添加一组事件处理程序
So instead what you would do is add one set of event handlers
给那一百个人的共同父母。
to the common parent of that hundred.
共同的父辈会截取所有的事件
And that common parent would intercept all of the events and
根据需要移动所有孩子。
move all the children as needed.
我不认为系统变得如此重要了
I don't think it matters anymore with the systems have gotten so
比在噪音中快多了，但是
much faster that it's in the noise, but
它仍然在模型中，看你仍然需要注意它。
it's still in the model see you still need to be aware of it.
你要做的一件事就是取消冒泡，所以
One thing you have to do is cancel bubbling, so
在某一点上，一些节点已经处理了一切并且它说，
at some point some node has taken care of everything and it says,
请不要告诉我父母，一切都在控制之中。
please don't tell my parents, it's under control and.
有两种方法可以做到这一点，你需要两种方法都能做到。
And there are two ways to do that and you need to be able to do it both ways.
有时您希望阻止默认操作
And sometimes you want to prevent the default action
在浏览器本身的所有东西都关闭后，可能会想要做一些事情。
after everything is down in the browser itself may want to do something.
可能想要提交表单或
May want to submit a form or or
把注意力放在某事上如果你不想让它发生，你就可以阻止它发生。
give focus to something if you don't want that to happen, you prevent that.
有三种方法可以防止这种情况的发生
And there are three ways to prevent that from happening and
你必须把所有这些都做好。
you have to do all of those as well.